

# SWATI AGGARWAL



A Software Developer with 3.9 years of experience in the diverse domain, seeking to enhance my working capabilities, professional skills, business efficiencies and to serve a company whose vision makes me nervous and this world a better place.



### **EXPERIENCE**

## SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### BTOI Technologies (Sep 2017 - Present)

GST Return filing and Invoices/ Purchase Project: It aims at easing the process of tax filing and creates different types of invoices and purchases for customers, companies, and businesses. Files GSTR1, GSTR2, and GSTR3B for every month.

Client: Lexplosion

#### Key Worked Areas:

- > Interacted with Client for the requirement gathering, system analysis and finalization of technical/functional specifications.
- > Handling full life cycle development including development, unit testing, system testing, troubleshooting, debugging of the software and managing smooth implementation via an Agile process.
- > Experience in working on Software Development platforms like Github, Bitbucket.

http://komplitax.com/









#### TECHNICAL CONSULTANT

#### PFRepo (Aug - Sep 2017)

Pf Repo is a digital repository to maintain your career portfolio in real time.

https://pfrepo.me/









#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### IBM India Pvt. Ltd. (Sep 2014 - Sep 2017)

LMS (Lead Management System): LMS manages and tracks all its prospective customers, information about successful lead and failed lead.

Client: Bharti Airtel

Tools/Technologies Used: Rational Software Architect, Rational Clear Case, Rational Team Concert, Rational Clear Quest, IBM DB2, SVN, Aqua Data Studio, Struts 1.2, IBM WebSphere v6.1, Servlets, JSP's

#### Key Worked Areas:

- > Analyzed the requirements and developed Java application modules.
- ➤ Involved in Unit Testing, User Acceptance Testing, and Bug Fixing.
- > Implemented logging mechanism using log4j for tracking errors and debugging.
- > Wrote Database queries and optimization of queries







Bharti Mediation: Mediation is a process of collecting and processing usage data from networked devices usually for billing and fraud management purposes.

Client: Bharti Airtel

Tools/Technologies Used: WinSCP, Putty, Rational Clear Case, Rational Clear Quest, Unix

#### Key Result Areas:

- > Analyzed the requirements and developed full end to end streams including Decoder, Business Logic Node, and Encoder.
- > Involved in Unit Testing, User Acceptance Testing, and Bug Fixing.

https://www.ibm.com/in-en/



# INTERNSHIP PROJECTS

#### PROJECT TRAINEE

#### Delhi Sectretariat (Jul - Aug 2013)

Made a Project titled "Data Mining of Unique Identification Authority of India Project".

http://www.delhi.gov.in/





# SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT INTERN

#### National Fertilizers Ltd. (Jun - Jul 2013)

Developed a Software Application for the Organization to manage their assets using JSP, Servlets, CSS.

http://www.nationalfertilizers.com/









## **OWN PROJECTS**

REACT-API-INTEGRATION-TEST

This is an application to integrate github login with your code.

https://github.com/Swats93/Test



PERFORMANCE-ANALYSIS-JS Made contributions in this repository. It does performance analysis of javascript of map, reduce, filter, find, loops and lodash library functions.

https://github.com/Swats93/ Performance-Analysis-JS



NODE-EXPRESS-MONGODB-STARTER-KIT This is a starter kit that helps you get started with Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Es6.

https://github.com/Swats93/learn-api







NODE-EXPRESS-POSTGRESQL-SEQUELIZE-STARTER- A starter kit that helps you get started with Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Es6.

https://github.com/Swats93/ node-express-postgresql-sequelize-starter-kit







## **PUBLICATIONS**

### TECHNOLOGY RELATED

1. https://medium.com/@garg.swati93/react-js-optimisation-techniques-a66aa9aea202

## **EDUCATION**

B.TECH COMPUTER SCIENCE

GGSIPU (2010 - 2014) with 81.51%. http://www.ipu.ac.in/